Privacy Policy 

Print

Date of Last Revision: December 13th, 2022

Introduction

This Privacy Policy applies to data collection practices by Rave Wireless, Inc. (“Rave Mobile Safety,”

“we” or “us”) via Rave Mobile Safety products including Rave Alert (getrave.com), Rave Panic

Button, the Rave Guardian mobile app, and the Rave Smart911 service, (each, a “Site” and

collectively the “Sites”) and shall apply to your use of the Sites and their capabilities and services

(“Services”). This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Rave Mobile Safety collects and uses

information from you (“you”) on the Sites.

We are committed to protecting your privacy in compliance with all pertinent laws and regulations.

Our Privacy Policy explains: (1) what information we collect and why we collect it; (2) how we use

and share that information; (3) the choices we offer you, including how to access and update

information, including the following topics:

1\. When this Privacy Policy Applies

2\. Terms of Use

3\. Information We Collect

4\. How We Use Information We Collect

5\. Our Legal Basis for Collecting Personal Data

6\. Information We Share

7\. Consequences of Your Failure to Provide Personal Data

8\. Our Retention of Your Personal Data

9\. Your Choices regarding Accessing, Updating or Deleting Your Personal Data

10\. European Users’ Rights with Respect to Personal Data

11\. Our Opt-in/Out-out Policy

12\. Third Party Links

13\. International Transfer

14\. How We Protect Personal Data

15\. Children

16\. Direct Marketing and “Do Not Track” Signals

17\. Rights of California Residents

18\. Smart911 Additional Terms

19\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

20\. How to Contact Us

Please familiarize yourself with our privacy practices that are described here and let us know if you

have any questions. By using the Sites and the mobile apps, you confirm your acceptance of this

Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites or mobile apps.

Irrespective of the country you live in, you authorize us to transfer, store, and use your information in

the United States and Canada in the manner described in this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise

agreed upon between Rave Mobile Safety and our customer (which typically would be your school or

employer). The privacy and data protection laws and rules regarding when government authorities

may access data may vary from those in the country where you live. Learn more about our data

transfer operations in the “International Transfer” section below. If you do not agree to the transfer,

storage and use of your information in the United States and Canada, you must not use the Sites.

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please submit a request

to privacy@ravemobilesafety.com.

When this Privacy Policy Applies

Our Privacy Policy applies to the Services offered by Rave Mobile Safety in the Introduction section

above and excludes services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy

Policy.

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals, including

products or sites that may be displayed to you by Rave Mobile Safety, or other sites linked from our

Services or Sites. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies

and organizations who advertise our Services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags and other

technologies to serve and offer relevant ads.

Terms of Use

By accessing or using the Sites or Services in any manner, you also agree to be bound by Rave

Mobile Safety's Terms of Use for the service or application you are using (the “Agreement”). Please

read the Agreement carefully. If you do not accept all of the terms and conditions contained in or

incorporated by reference into the Agreement, please do not use the Sites or Services.

Information We Collect

We collect information, including Personal Data, to provide better Services to all our users. We use

the term “Personal Data” to refer to any information that identifies or can be used to identify an

individual. Common examples of Personal Data include: first and last name, address, email address,

business email address, organization name, phone number, digital identity such as a login name or

handle, information about your device, and certain metadata.

“Sensitive Personal Data” refers to a smaller subset of Personal Data which is considered more

sensitive to the individual, such as race and ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical

beliefs, trade-union membership, genetic or biometric information, physical or mental health

information, medical insurance data, or sexual orientation. Rave Mobile Safety does not collect or

use Sensitive Personal Data through our Sites and Products and asks that you do not provide

Sensitive Personal Data to us.

We collect Personal Data in the following ways:

1\. Information You Give to Us

When registering for our Services or creating a subscriber account, you may choose to provide us

with Personal Data such as your name, phone number, email address, physical address,

geolocation, and medical or household information.

When using our Services, you may provide us with information sent between you and individuals

authorized to administer our Services. This information you may elect to share with the Services

includes location data, address data and phone contact data. You may also provide us with Personal

Data about yourself when your report a problem or have. a question about our Sites or Services.

Please note that if you do not provide us with Personal Data, your ability to use certain aspects of

our Sites and Services may be limited.

2\. Information We Obtain from Your Use of Our Sites

We collect certain information automatically, such as your operating system version, browser type,

and internet service provider. When you use our Sites or Services, we automatically collect and store

this information in service logs. This includes: details of how you used our Sites and Services;

Internet protocol address; and cookies that uniquely identify your browser. We may also collect and

process information about your actual location. The information we collect automatically is statistical

data and may or may not include Personal Data, but we may maintain it or associate it with Personal

Data we collect in other ways or receive from third parties.

3\. Information our Customers May Give Us About You

Others who may have contracted for our Services for your use, such as your employer or your

school, have the option to provide us with Personal Data and your eligibility to use the Services they

purchased. The information provided by your employer or school may include your name, phone

number, email address, street address, geolocation (if you opt-in for the Services, and such other

data as you may request or it determines is appropriate.

4\. Cookies

We and our partners use cookies and web log files to collect and store information when you visit or

use one of our Services, and this may include using cookies or similar technologies to identify your

browser or device. With both cookies and log files, the information that we collect, and share is

anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone

number, or email address. A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You

may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser.

However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to access or have the benefit of certain parts

of our Services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our

system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Services. For more information about

our use of cookies, including details on how to opt-out of certain cookies, please see our Cookie

Policy.

How We Use Information We Collect

We use your Personal Data in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was collected

or authorized by you, including:

1. To inform you about Services available from Rave Mobile Safety;

2. To authorize access to our Sites and Services;

3. To provide you with Services;

4. To improve our customer service;

5. To respond to and support your school or employer regarding its use of the Sites and

Services;

6. To comply with all applicable legal requirements. and

7. To investigate possible fraud or other violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy

and/or attempts to harm our users.

We use the information we collect from our Sites to provide, maintain, and improve them, to develop

new Services, and to protect our company and our customers.

We may use information collected from cookies and other technologies to improve your user

experience and the overall quality of our Services. For example, by saving your language

preferences, we’ll be able to have our Services appear in the language you prefer. We may use your

personal information to see which web pages you visit at our Sites and we may then develop

statistics that help us understand how our visitors use our Sites and how to improve them. We may

also use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice at

the time of collection.

We will ask for your consent before using information for a purpose other than those set out in this

Privacy Policy.

Our Legal Basis for Collecting Personal Data

Whenever we collect Personal Data from you, we may do so on the following legal bases:

1\. Your consent to such collection and use;

2\. Out of necessity for the performance of an agreement between us and you, such as your

agreement to use our Services and products;

3\. Our legitimate business interest, including but not limited to the following circumstances where

collecting or using Personal Data is necessary:

●

● Intra-company transfers of customer data for administrative purposes;

● Product development and enhancement, where the processing enables us to

enhance, modify, personalize, or otherwise improve our Services and

communications for the benefit of our customers, and to better understand how

people interact with our Sites and Services;

● Fraud detection and prevention;

● Enhancement of our cybersecurity, including improving the security of our network

and information systems; and

● General business operations and diligence;

provided that, in each circumstance, we will weigh the necessity of our processing for the purpose

against your privacy and confidentiality interests, including taking into account your reasonable

expectations, the impact of processing, and any safeguards which are or could be put in place to

protect your privacy. In all circumstances, we will limit such processing for our legitimate business

interest to what is necessary for its purposes.

Information We Share

We do not share Personal Data collected through the Sites or Services with companies,

organizations and individuals outside of Rave Mobile Safety unless one of the following

circumstances applies:

1. With your consent. We may share Personal Data with companies, organizations, or individuals

outside of Rave Mobile Safety when we have your consent to do so.

2. Enterprise accounts. Your employer or school may have offered you access to our Services. In

such a circumstance, we may share Personal Data you provide with your employer or school so that

it can review and manage your use of such enterprise Services.

3. For external processing. We may provide Personal Data to our affiliates or other trusted

businesses or partners to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with this

Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. These third parties,

including, without limitation, , 9-1-1 or equivalent services, fire, police, emergency medical,

emergency management, campus safety officials, public health services, services providing

safety-related monitoring and response (collectively, “Emergency Service Providers”) and

communication service providers. Examples of permitted disclosure of Personal Data include:

1. Your wireless phone number may be submitted to participating Emergency Service

Providers, in order to locate the device during an emergency or transmit messages

that you send or receive. We may store or archive snapshots of then-current

Subscriber information as it’s made available to Emergency Service Providers, for

the period of time dictated by their record keeping policies. Such third parties may

use such information to send emergency and general interest notifications to you via

various communication methods (e.g. voice calls, text messaging, email, etc.).

2. In the event an emergency call or other direct communication is placed from your

phone or device, and provided that the Emergency Service Provider receiving the

call uses our Services, your information may be displayed on the answering

operator's workstation screen or made available to emergency responders.

3. In the event a non-9-1-1 call is made to an Emergency Service Provider from your

phone and is then routed into a 9-1-1 system, if the receiving 9-1-1 agency uses our

Services your information may be displayed on the 9-1-1 operator's workstation

screen. In these situations, once information is passed to the local 9-1-1 authorities,

we no longer have control over the transmission of the information. It may be

conveyed verbally over an unsecured radio or transmitted in some other way to the

responding emergency response team or others.

4. In the event an Emergency Service Provider uses the Services’ database query

tools, and your information includes an address within the querying provider's

jurisdiction, and a portion of your information matches the provider's query criteria,

and if you have elected to participate in this portion of our Services, your information

will be displayed in the search results presented to that provider.

It is our policy to only share Personal Data with contractors, service providers and other third parties

who are bound by obligations to keep Personal Data confidential and use it only for the purposes for

which we disclose it to them. Under certain circumstances, you may avoid having us share your

information with our business partners and vendors by not granting us permission to share it. Not

granting us permission to share your information with our business partners or vendors may limit

your access to their services through the Sites. We do not share Personal Data with third parties for

their own marketing purposes.

4. For Legal Reasons. We may share Personal Data with companies, organizations or individuals

outside of Rave Mobile Safety if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or

disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

1. Comply with an applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable

governmental request.

2. Enforce applicable terms of use, including investigation of potential violations.

3. Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.

4. Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Rave Mobile Safety, our

users or the public, as required or permitted by law.

We attempt to notify users about legal demands for their Personal Data when appropriate in our

judgment, unless prohibited by law or court order or when the request is an emergency. We may

dispute such demands when we believe, in our discretion, that the requests are overbroad, vague or

lack proper authority, but we do not promise to challenge every demand.

The specific circumstances under which we may share your Personal Data will vary based on the

information you provide, the Services you elect to participate in, and how you use the Services.

5. Business Transfers. As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, sell, or share assets

in connection with, for example, a merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets, or bankruptcy.

In such transactions, Personal Data about our users is often a transferred business asset. In the

event that Rave Mobile Safety itself or substantially all of our assets are acquired, Personal Data

about our users may be one of the transferred assets to enable the new owner to provide the

Services to you in compliance with our agreements, this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

Subsequent to the change of ownership, the new owner will be solely responsible for compliance

with this Privacy Policy (or a replacement to which you agree) and the law.

6. Aggregate Site Use Information. Our Services may automatically collect usage information,

such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our Sites and users who use our Services. We use

this information in aggregate form and not in a manner that would identify you personally. We may

share aggregate and anonymized/ pseudonymized Personal Data to advertisers and other third

parties in order to promote or describe use of the Sites and Services.

Rave Mobile Safety is not responsible for the actions or inactions of any third party receiving your

Personal Data as permitted herein. These third parties may have their own respective privacy

policies governing their use, protection and disclosure of your Personal Data.

Consequences of Your Failure to Provide Personal Data

Your provision of Personal Data is required in order to use certain parts of our Sites and Services. If

you fail to provide such Personal Data, you may not be able to access and use our Services on our

Sites or parts of our Services available via the Sites.

Our Retention of Your Personal Data

We may retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the original purpose for

collection. We keep your Personal Data for no longer than reasonably necessary for your use of our

products and Services and for a reasonable period of time afterward to conform to legal and

business requirements.

If your account is removed from our Sites and Services, we generally delete account information

within thirty (30) days of account removal, except that we retain your Personal Data even after you

have closed your account if reasonably necessary to address our legitimate business interests,

including to comply with our legal obligations (including law enforcement requests), meet regulatory

requirements, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, maintain security,

prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our Terms of Service, or fulfill your request to “unsubscribe” from

further messages from us.

Your Choices regarding Accessing, Updating or Deleting Your

Personal Data

Whenever you use our Services, we aim to provide you with choices about how we use your

Personal Data. We also will provide you with access to your Personal Data. If that information is

wrong, we will give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that

information for legitimate business or legal purposes. Subject to applicable law, you may obtain a

copy of personal information we maintain about you or you may update or correct inaccuracies in

that information through your Profile or Account, or by contacting us

at privacy@ravemobilesafety.com. To help protect your privacy and maintain security, we will take

steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the information. In addition, if you believe

that personal information, we maintain about you is inaccurate, subject to applicable law you may

have the right to request that we correct or amend the information by contacting us as indicated in

the How to Contact Us section below.

You may update your information stored on the Sites at any time, as applicable to your Sites and

Services:

1. Where you have been given access to the Sites and Services, you may update your

information in the "My Profile" and/or "My Account" areas.

2. Where your organization provides your information on your behalf, you must contact the

organization to access this information or request changes to it.

You may also update or correct information about yourself by emailing us

at privacy@ravemobilesafety.com.

We may contact you to request that you update your Personal Data on a regular basis to ensure its

integrity for the purposes of ongoing data management.

European Users’ Rights with Respect to Personal Data

Some data protection laws, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation

(“GDPR”), provide you with certain rights in connection with Personal Data you have shared with us.

If you are resident in the European Economic Area, you have the following rights, all of which we

provide you, as described in this Privacy Policy:

1. The right to be informed: You are entitled to be informed of the use of your Personal Data.

2. The right of access: You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Data which we

hold about you.

3. The right of correction: You have the right to request correction or changes of your

Personal Data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date.

4. The right to be forgotten: You have the right to request us, at any time, to delete your

Personal Data from our servers and to erase your Personal Data when it is no longer

necessary for us to retain such data. Note, however, that deletion of your Personal Data will

likely impact your ability to use our Services.

5. The right to object (opt-out): You have the right to opt-out of certain uses of your Personal

Data, such as direct marketing, at any time.

6. The right to data portability: You have the right to a “portable” copy of your Personal Data

that you have submitted to us. Generally, this means your right to request that we move,

copy or transmit your Personal Data stored on our servers / IT environment to another

service provider’s servers / IT environment.

7. The right to refuse to be subjected to automated decision making, including

profiling: You have the right not to be subject to a decision and insist on human intervention

if the decision is based on automated processing and produces a legal effect or a similarly

significant effect on you.

8. The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority: Should you do that, we

encourage you also to contact us using the contact information below, and we will consider

your request in accordance with applicable laws.

Our Opt-in/Opt-out Policy

By providing an email address or other contact information on the Rave Mobile Safety Sites or it is

provided with your consent by your school or employer, you agree that we may contact you in the

event of a change in this Privacy Policy, to provide you with any Services-related notices, or to

provide you with information about our events, invitations, or related educational information.

We currently provide the following opt-out opportunities:

1. At any time, you can follow a link provided in offers, newsletters or other messages (except

for Service notice emails) received from us to unsubscribe from the Services.

2. At any time, you can contact us through privacy@ravemobilesafety.com or the address

provided below to unsubscribe from the Services and opt-out of our right per your consent

under the terms of this Privacy Policy to share your Personal Data.

3. Where you have been given access to the Sites and Services, you may update your

subscription settings in your account.

4. Where your organization provides your information on your behalf, you must contact the

organization to access this information or request changes to your information.

Third Party Links

The Sites may contain links to webpages operated by parties other than Rave Mobile Safety. We do

not control such websites and are not responsible for their contents or the privacy policies or other

practices of such websites. Our inclusion of links to such websites does not imply any endorsement

of the material on such websites or any association with their operators. Further, it is up to the user

to take precautions to ensure that whatever links the user selects or software the user downloads

from such websites is free of such items as viruses, worms, trojan horses, defects and other items of

a destructive nature. These websites and services may have their own privacy policies, which the

user will be subject to upon linking to the third party's website. Rave Mobile Safety strongly

recommends that each user review the third party's terms and policies.

International Transfer

We are committed to complying with applicable laws, regulations and mandatory government

standards regarding the protection of Personal Data.

Since we are a global organization, Personal Data and any additional information submitted may be

used globally in connection with employment, business processes within Rave Mobile Safety, or

communicating with our clients. Therefore, Personal Data may be transferred to other Rave Mobile

Safety entities worldwide, where it will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and laws

that are applicable in each country. Countries where we process data may have laws which are

different, and potentially not as protective, as the laws of your own country.

If we transfer your Personal Data out of your jurisdiction, we will implement suitable safeguards and

rely on legally provided mechanisms to lawfully transfer data across borders to ensure that your

Personal Data is protected.

How We Protect Personal Data

Rave Mobile Safety maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect

the user's Personal Data and information against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction,

loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. We implement appropriate technical and organizational

measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk, taking into account technological

reality, cost, the scope, context and purposes of processing weighted against the severity and

likelihood that the processing could threaten individual rights and freedoms. For example, we use

commercially reasonable security measures such as encryption, firewalls, and transport layer

security (TLS) or hypertext transfer protocol secure (HTTPS) to protect Personal Data. However,

Rave Mobile Safety cannot guarantee the security of user account or other personal information.

Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, could compromise the

security of user information at any time.

Children

In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), we do not market to or

knowingly collect any information about children under the age of 13 unless and until a relevant

institution has provided consent and authorization for a child under the age of 13 to use the Sites or

Services and for us to collect information from such child. If you are a minor less than 13 years old,

please do not register for Services or provide any personal information about you to us. If you are

less than 16 years old, do not provide any personal health information about yourself to us. If you

believe that we might have inadvertently collected personal information from a child under age 13 or

personal health information from a child under age 16 without proper consent, please contact us

at privacy@ravemobilesafety.com. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected the personal

information of a child under 13, or equivalent minimum age depending on jurisdiction, without proper

consent, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.

Direct Marketing and “Do Not Track” Signals

Rave Mobile Safety does not track its customers over time or across third party websites to provide

targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some

third-party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which

enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, your browser may

include controls to block and delete cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, to allow you to

opt out of data collection through those technologies.

Rights of California Residents

California residents are entitled under the California Consumer Privacy Act to contact us for various

purposes, including to request information about whether we have disclosed personal information to

third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not disclose personal information to third

parties for their direct marketing purposes. California residents have the right to be informed as to

what personal information about them we may have, how we collected and may use that information

and how to have it corrected or deleted and may request further information about our compliance

with this law by contacting us by one of the means listed in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

Smart911 Additional Terms

If you are a Smart911 subscriber, the following additional terms apply:

1. You may choose to provide additional personal information in your subscriber account. The

types of additional personal information collected may include driver’s license number,

license plate number, photos, and date of birth. You may also include personal health

information such as medical and health conditions, medical devices and medications. This

additional information is optional and is provided at your sole discretion. It is your

responsibility to determine how much or how little information you wish to make available.

2. If you are a legal guardian or parent of a minor, you may provide the service with personal

information including personal health information about the minor and we will treat it under

this Privacy Policy.

3. You can change your subscriber account at any time, whether it is the information supplied at

registration, as part of maintaining your subscriber account, or anything else. You may add,

modify, or remove information on your subscriber account by logging into www.smart911.com

and accessing your profile. You understand that we use your personal information to provide

you with the Services. If you refuse to provide us with the personal information we require or

later withdraw your consent to use and disclose this information, we may no longer be able

to provide you with these Services.

4. You may add or remove which Services you choose to participate in at any time, by logging

into www.smart911.com and modifying your preferences.

5. You may cancel any or all of the Services at any time by logging into www.smart911.com,

and accessing account settings

6. In addition to the possible uses of your Personal Data referenced elsewhere in this Privacy

Policy, (a) your location and subscriber information may be shared with other individuals that

you have designated as guardians; (b) in the event you send a “Tip”, your subscriber

information may be viewed by an Emergency Service Provider, unless the Emergency

Service Provider receiving your Tip has configured the service to be anonymous; and (c)

when you invite a guardian, we may send such person a message on your behalf using your

name and contact details. We may also send reminders to them in your name.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. The latest version will always be available here

and the most recent revision date will be indicated at the top of this page. We will not reduce your

rights under this Privacy Policy without notice. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page

and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain

Services or products, email notification of privacy policy changes). Please check this page

occasionally to make sure you are aware of any updates

How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us via email or phone, or by

writing to us as follows:

Rave Mobile Safety

Attn: Privacy Policy Inquiry

492 Old Connecticut Path

2nd Floor

Framingham, MA 01701

Toll-free: 888-605-7164

privacy@ravemobilesafety.com
